Luke McHugh

16 Old Castle Road Newtownstewart BT78 4HX Contact Number: 07568511896

E-Mail: lukemchugh18@outlook.com

Summary

Motivated labourer with 4 years of progressive experience in the engineering and manufacturing industry. Offering expertise in CAD, polyurethane operations and metal fabrication, with aptitude in labour. Energetic self-starter and team builder able to navigate high-stress situations and achieve goals on time and under budget. I am also an assistant coach focused on developing, training, and managing junior competitors.

Experience

Bartender

Silverbirches Omagh

September 2018 to April 2019

My main duties as a bartender include:

- Received beverage orders from wait staff and delivered beverages to guests.
- Ordered and maintained inventory of bar products, including alcohol, soft drinks and supplies to drive high volume of sales.
- Confirmed customers ages for alcohol service and discontinued service to intoxicated guests.
- Kept detailed inventories of bar supplies and kept work areas stocked to maintain workflow efficiently.
- Recognised VIP customers immediately and provided special treatment, including preferred tables.
- Maintained neat personal appearance.
- Delivered quality food and beverage service to guests quickly.
- Greeted guests in a timely and professional manner.
- Monitored glassware and stemware inventory.
- Checked patron's identification to ensure minimum age requirements for consumption of alcoholic beverages.
- Upheld high standard of cleanliness in all work areas.
- Maintained facility compliance with health codes, sanitation requirements and licence regulations.
- Advertised, marketed and recommended drink options to guests to increase guest satisfaction.

- Managed customer service by training staff, overseeing operations and resolve issues quickly.
- Kept close track of bar tabs and transferred open tabs to dining area seamlessly, providing pleasant dining experience to customers and smoothing process for wait staff.
- Stocked beer and wine coolers.
- Served each guest with sincere, positive, pleasant and enthusiastic attitude.
- Cleaned and filled ice bins.
- Processed over 100 transactions daily using cards, cash and voucher payment systems, applying any eligible coupons or promotions.
- Made product recommendations to customers based on preference, food pairings and special promotions.

Manual Labourer

Arolco Ireland Castlederg

July 2017 to Current

My main duties as a labourer include:

- Supported fabrication team by offering my assistance and time to help complete tasks.
- Promoted several ideas for improving the online Services which increased overall productivity.
- Kept sites clean and tidy by implementing a new cleaning strategy.
- Received consistently positive feedback for labour service, continually working with energy and enthusiasm.
- Delivered an exceptional level of service to each customer by listening to concerns and answering questions.
- Carried out essential labour tasks to improve day-to-day manufacturing and engineering operations.
- Supported engineers in improving operations and resolving issues to deliver topnotch customer service.
- Developed expertise and knowledge in CAD (Computer Aided Design) to ensure consistent delivery of outstanding CAD services.
- Supported CAD technicians in improving operations and resolving issues to deliver top-notch customer service.

Coach

Newtownstewart St. Eugene's GAA club July 2019 to Current My Main Duties as a coach include:

- Volunteered to manage different teams within my local GAA club.
- Designed strength and conditioning programmes.
- Facilitated training on Fitness and other aspects of the game.
- Managed travel arrangements for coaching staff and players.
- Worked with fundraisers, parents and school administrators to handle support functions.
- Encouraged club members to participate in fundraisers.
- Maintained safety of training, individual exercises, and equipment usage.
- Encouraged team members to become stronger, more agile athletes and more successful competitors.
- Upheld safety of all team members during practice, exercise, and game play.
- Readied team to compete in tournaments and other special games.
- Ran drills and practices to help children develop and improve sports skill levels.
- Kept supplies, equipment and facilities in a neat, organised and performanceoriented fashion.
- Set clear performance targets and evaluated player and team achievements.

Education

University of Ulster Jordanstown Belfast 2019 - Present Bachelor of Science Interactive Computing

Christian Brothers Grammar School Omagh 2012 - 2019

A-Levels	
Subject	Grade
Sports Studies	Distinction*
Digital Technology	С
Professional Business Services	D

GCSEs	
Subject	Grade
Digital Technology	A
English Language	A
English Literature	В
Maths	В
Spanish	В
Double Award Science	BC
Religious Education	С
Learning for Life and Work	С
Business Studies	D

Key Skills

A few key skills I have acquired through my employment and developed through my time at my places of education include:

- Strong organisational skills
- Strong communication skills
- Problem solving
- Sport rules and regulations
- In-depth knowledge of Gaelic football
- Foundation GAA coaching certification
- Safety trained
- 3D design and simulation software
- Deadline driven

Personal Information

I am 19 years old and I am currently studying for my degree in Interactive computing at the University of Ulster. I am a hard worker and I always ensure that I complete my job to the best of my ability. Through my time at the Omagh CBS and my different areas of employment I have developed good communication skills; I am able to work in a team or independently; I have also developed good problem-solving skills during my time at school.

Interests

My main interests would involve:

- Sports Gaelic football, Basketball, Soccer, working out, Running, Cycling, Table tennis, Walking, Hiking, and other team sports.
- Travelling
- Volunteering
- Socialising
- Music
- Video games